

Balthazar Ely

- Phone number: 303-518-9973 Email address: balthazar.elyj@gmail.com
- Web: balthazar-ely.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/balthazarely
- Github: github.com/balthazarely



Profile

I am a web developer with professional experience as a graphic designer. I am proficient in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, and have experience with full-stack web development technologies and frameworks such as Vue, React, Firebase, and MongoDB. My previous professional experience as a designer includes managing the graphic design department for a national level multi-family investment company, specializing in logo design, marketing strategies, print production, and managing over 180 apartment websites.



Work experience

10/2019 – present Denver

Front End Developer OneTen (DISH Network)

Work includes creating dynamic creative optimization (DCO) HTML5 banners for Dish network, SlingTV, Dish Latino, OnTech Smart Home Services, and Dish Commercial.

- Develop HTML Banners in DCO format, integrating dynamic variables and imagery, that have millions of impressions across the web each day.
- Leverage JavaScript libraries such as GSAP, HTML Canvas, and Flashtalking Ad Server to create interactive banners and click-through rates.
- Collaborate with the in-house design team to help inform the design and functionality of interactive banners.
- Developed banners for SlingTV ad campaign that set a company record with over 70,000 new sign-ups in under 1 hour.
- Perform cross-browser testing, ensuring banners display correctly on all major browsers and mobile.
- Led initiative to update and optimize banners, incorporate new ES6 features, HTML Canvas, and adding dynamic variables to GSAP animations, reducing average development time from one week to just one day per banner set.
- Work with design applications, such as Photoshop, Sketch, and Illustrator to optimize and compress graphics for web use.

06/2018 - 03/2019 Denver

Senior Marketing Designer Monarch Investment & Management Group

Responsibilities included designing marketing campaigns for prospective residents, as well as internal marketing and employee retention.

- Developed and managed websites and branding needs for over 140 apartment communities across 14 different states, as well as multiple social media profiles for each property.
- Collaborated with regional teams across the national apartment portfolio to develop regional branding and advertising campaigns.
- Designed all print collateral, including brochures, business cards, and logos, and web design/UX for websites for over 180 communities.
- Supervised graphic design projects for corporate-level departments, including recruiting materials, corporate advertisements, company newsletters, and other internal design work.
- Promoted to the Senior Marketing Designer role on July 10th, 2019, after working as the Marketing Designer for two years.



06/2016 - 06/2018 Denver **Marketing Designer**

Monarch Investment & Management Group

Graphic designer overseeing the design of marketing campaigns for prospective residents, as well as internal marketing and employee retention marketing tasks.

05/2014 - 06/2016 Denver Digital Marketing Coordinator
Monarch Investment & Management Group

Developed and manage websites and branding needs for over 140 apartment communities across 14 different states, as well as multiple social media profiles for each property



Education

06/2019 - 10/2019 Denver

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly

Learned full-stack web development in a 400+ hour immersive course, specializing in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Python, and other frameworks and libraries.

2010 - 2014 Denver

B.S. Business Administration University of Colorado Denver

Emphasis in Marketing



Skills

Javascript	jQuery	HTML5	SaSS/CSS3
Bootstrap, Bulma	Node	Vue/Vuex	React
Firebase	GSAP	Git/Github	Adobe Suite
Sketch	Print Production	Web Design	Graphic Design



Hobbies



Travel



Fitness



Skiing



Friends

Electronic Music



Learning JS Libraries